Kar do
[music] Kar
do
aur sango
that namaste friends welcome to my YouTube
channel Only Investors friends whenever
blocks of a company i.e. number of shares are
sold or bought in a large quantity
then ultimately you know we get to
see a huge impact on the
share price and most of the
time when block deal happens it is related to the stock
so it is considered a bad thing
for the company and mostly there are retail
investors, when they hear this then
they get scared that we should liquidate this
company because there has been a huge
selling through block deal i.e. some big
company has exited from the company which we have acquired i.e. in which
we had also invested,
one of that big companies has done its test in that big company, so the
news of that block deal has come out due to which people should
liquidate
their stake, their own investment, so
we often hear such things in the market, so
friends
today's video is related to this thing along with a news and there are
some other points too, this is with you in this  I
will share it in the video, so please watch this video till the
end so that you can understand each of my
points well. Friends, there is a
company named Ek. That company
wants to sell its 3.5% holding in ICICI Lombard through a block deal and the
web login has just started, so this is
related news, basically, about this
airline. Now we will see some details
which are very important to see,
you will learn some things from here.
If you watch this video till the end, so
basically friends, on October 4, it was noticed by ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company
that its
shareholder, that is, a very big
shareholder, an insurance firm named
X Age,
wants to sell its 3.57% stake. If we
talk about the number of seats, then it becomes 1.75 crore
shares in this pack. The
price of the share is being discussed from Rs. 1576. Now you
can see here that
these shares will be sold in the price range of Rs. 1497 to Rs. 1576.
Friends, in our stock
market, such  We often hear in the news
that a company is
exiting from another company, sometimes it is
selling its stake in that company.
Friends, this is
not negative news, that is, you
cannot directly declare this news as negative
until we check the fundamentals of the company. That is, let us
assume that the news is
related to ICICI Lombard, so now we will start with the fundamentals of ICICI Lombard.
If the fundamentals of that company appear to be weakening, that is, the
business of the company appears to be weakening, then we
can consider this news as negative and exit our
stake.
But if the fundamentals of the company are still there and
we are hearing news
that someone is exiting from this
company, then we cannot consider this news as negative because the
company itself has not exited.
Those fundamentals of the company are the same as the
business. So, let us
quickly take a look at the fundamentals.  Let's take an
overview of the fundamentals of the company.
Friends,
before going towards the fundamentals, I would like to show you one more thing here. A
machine of the size of this heart is being installed. It is worth around Rs
2621 crore. This means that it is very
big. This can be a block deal. Friends,
if we talk about the net income of the company, then
we have data here which is available from 2012.
We saw the net income of the company going down in the last year. It is
seen here at Rs 4.6 crore.
After that, a lot of
good improvement was seen in the company. From 2013 onwards,
you can see that the net income
of the company is seen at Rs 352 crore.
In 2014, we saw Rs 520 crore.
Vikram, if we talk about the next three years, then
in 2015 we saw Rs 525 crore, in 2016 Rs 507 crore and
here we are seeing a small drop in the
income, but after that the company  It
recovered again, that is, it made a comeback and
in 2017, the company's net income is
seen to be 70 crores. After that,
if we talk about the next four years, then you
can see here 80 crores,
1000, 1193 and if we talk about 2021, then
1408 crores. Friends, the business of the company is
clearly visible from here, it is
growing very well with time.
Talking about the share holding pattern of the company,
we are seeing a very impressive pattern. The
promoter has a holding of 48.08 percent, the
mutual fund has 8
percent, domestic equity is about 2% and
Aishwarya has a very big share. You
can see here that more than 2017 percent
is seen
and we are seeing a holding of 31.65 percent with the retailers.
So basically,
friends, it is a good share holding pattern, there is nothing
bad in it.
After this, friends, it is
also very important to look at the balance sheet of the company.  If this happens, then let's
assume this and this Mike look. First of all, if
we talk about Swiss Rolls Royce,
you can see here that we are getting a very
good opportunity to learn from this.
For about 70-60 crores only, there is no
harm in this, it is quite good that when it is there, then
let's talk about the long-term benefits of the company. The
company has been carrying debt for a long time.
You can see here that it is
425 crores, so it is fine,
if we look at the patient and with that, the
increase is so big, we are
seeing 425 crores. If we
talk about short-term boring, then you
can see here that now we are
seeing absolutely zero, so this is also a
good thing, so basically, it is looking good in the sale, there is
no bad benefit, that is,
we are not seeing any negative point here.
Friends, I am going to take a quick overview inside the balance sheet.
If we add any stock, then it is
not done so quickly, through which I can
quickly share it.  I am
adding this so that we can get
an overview of the fundamentals of the company. And the
news that we are hearing,
we see whether it is negative news or
not, should we make any changes in this company
or not, so for that I am
quickly analyzing some factors.
After this, friends, if we
talk about the returns of the stock, you can see here
that when the stock was listed on the 2017 temple,
it appeared here
and from then till today it has
given a return of 128 percent. If you look at its chart,
you can see that the chart is
showing us almost 1 consistency,
that some updates are being seen here. If we
talk about butter hot long-term, from
then till now,
except for Twenty20 and Musawwar year licking, that is, the
stock price has made a new one,
so this is also a plus point
for the company and for its fundamentals,
subscribe if we come back to UC again, such which
Block deals are often
seen in the market in surveys to sell stakes.
For example, the
SBI Cards group has increased its stake significantly in SBI Cards.
However, this does not mean
that the stock in SBI Cards is a very
good source and has very strong
fundamentals. Due to profit booking,
we cannot declare a stop or withdraw
from it. I would
like to provide a disclaimer here. I
also own SBI Cards, but I have
invested in it myself. Friends, similarly, if we
talk about ICICI Lombard,
many people who own this stock have messaged me.
Due to this, there is
no need to withdraw from it. Such profit booking is
often seen in the market. If we
look at the fundamentals of the stock, we can
see everything is fine. The company's
business is growing and everything is good. So, there is nothing to
fear. As long as the
fundamentals of the company remain strong, you
can definitely keep it in your portfolio. So,
friends, this was a short
video of mine on this marking update. If you  If you do
n't want to miss such market free daily updates then subscribe to Mirchi and my channel and turn on
notifications by clicking on the bell icon. Thank you friends
for watching today's video
[Music]
Ajay Ko